Santosh Karki

Glenroy 3046, Victoria / 0452 437 106 / Karki santosh@outlook.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Results-driven Web Developer with 3+ years of experience in designing, developing, and maintaining web applications. Proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies, with a strong ability to troubleshoot, problem-solve, and optimise code for efficiency. Seeking to leverage expertise in full stack development to contribute to innovative projects and drive organisational success.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- React | Next.js
- Node.js | Express.js
- Python
- REST API | GraphQL
- MongoDB | MySQL
- Adobe XD | Figma
- Github | Bitbucket
- Docker

- CI/CD
- Agile | SCRUM
- Problem-Solving
- Collaboration

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Successful Project Delivery: Consistently delivered high-quality front-end solutions that met or exceeded project requirements, deadlines, and client expectations that increase the revenue by 10%.

Performance Optimisation: Improved site performance optimisations that enhance the speed of the website loading times, rendering speed, and overall performance metrics, leading to positive user experience, growing site traffic by 50%, lead volume, and brand awareness.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AUSTIN HEALTH

Heidelberg VIC, 3084 Full Stack Developer Intern

Key responsibilities:

- Developed complex web applications using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and React.js, resulting in a 40% increase in user engagement metrics.
- Contributed to 10 bitbucket repositories, consistently meeting deadlines for team projects and maintaining a 92% code correctness rate.
- Wrote and kept up more than 100 Jest unit tests, resulting in a 70% code coverage.
- Contributed to the creation of three new features that were addressed in PI planning sessions with the leadership team and increased system performance rates by 10%..
- Implemented a comprehensive error handling system within the APIs, reducing downtime by 30% due to server-side issues.
- Created and implemented a patient registration form to schedule a visit with the physician, resulting in a 70% shorter wait time.

FUSEMACHINES NEPAL

FEB 2022 - MAR 2023

JUN 2023 - OCT 2023

Kathmandu, Nepal Full Stack Developer

Key responsibilities:

- Coded and implemented 3 new application features using Node.js and Express.js, increasing monthly revenue by 10%.
- Protected user data by implementing security best practices, such as input validation and CSRF protection, that secure customer privacy.
- Worked closely with senior developers to troubleshoot issues and reviews 50+ weekly code.

- Identified and fixed 20+ improvements to product design and functionality based on user experiences.
- Improved cross-functional team coordination by setting up automated notifications and alerts between Jira and Bitbucket, reducing miscommunication instances by 60%.
- Designed and optimised back-end systems using Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB, improving data retrieval and processing efficiency by 40%.

PROJECTS

Portfolio: Personal portfolio highlighted all my skills, experience, and projects.

Project link: https://santoskarki.live/

AFFOGATO: It is a Full Stack Restaurant website, developed using MERN.

Project link: https://main--affogato.netlify.app/

EDUCATION

Federation University, Ballarat Bachelor of Information Technology

MAR 2018 - MAR 2021

Monash Professional Pathways, Melbourne

Professional Year ICT

AUG 2021 - FEB 2022

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

• Australian Computer Society (ACS), Student member

AUG 2021 - AUG 2024

REFEREES

Available on request.